All that they are members of this community, I want to gratefully welcome you
to one of
their most interesting and biggest decisions which is to learn about influencer
marketing
from a company that has made very good from this strategy, from this marketing
method.
So that means to do this myself, the person who is talking behind the screen is
Santiago
Talavera, founder of Happy Flops.
And Happy Flops is one of the fastest growing e-comp companies in Europe and
this is thanks
for influencers.
So guys, without getting into too much time of the introduction, I want you to
do this
to the four topics that we would talk about and I will make this very simple
guys.
I'm not a course guy, I've never done this before but this is sincerely the
most genuine
way on how to do the best for you guys.
Basically taking my screen and doing guys like a drafting board and giving you
the best
sauce you will hear probably this year.
Happy Flops influencer story, I will tell you about this story, I will tell you
how we found
out about this strategy and I will also explain to you the most important thing
which is why
some influencers sell and why others don't.
The second topic will be to go a little bit more into depth, how to do research
, what
it means, how you can create your own list and how you can measure the risk
which is the
thing that we promised here, how do we measure people's trust on social media,
extremely
extremely important and critical once you are getting into influencers.
Then we will learn how to do outreach and build the setup for influencer
collaboration
which is really, really different from what other brands is doing and you will
be maybe
a little bit shocked how we do this and because there is different methods and
different ways
how to invest in an influencer but we will give and share with you guys the
most efficient
way.
And the last, what is important before the launch of influencers and then how
to build relationship
with performing influencers which is extremely important for your long term
growth.
So guys, I will start with my story.
Happy Flops were actually already selling for 10K a day.
This was when we were doing performance marketing with ads on, I think it was
Norway and Sweden
and it was going decently.
I think and I hope a lot of you guys already are at this stage which is of
course a very
well and good stage to be in selling already $10,000 a day, it's actually
pretty good.
So if you guys are already in this stage super nice, I congratulate you.
So what happened is that one day specifically March 25th of March 2022, it's
for nowhere
we did 20K on a day, and nobody from the company did know why.
We didn't know why because on our meta accounts it didn't say that we were
performing extra
or making any extra revenue from any specific ad or so.
So what I started to do is I logged in to Shopify and I started to call all the
customers because
there was no other way to find out.
So I did some calls, I think around 2030 calls to really be sure where did you
buy from.
I introduced myself, hey, this is Santiago, founder of Happy Flops, thank you
for purchasing
our product, I just wondered where did you find us and actually all of them,
majority
of them were pointing at one person on social media.
This day changed my life for sure and this day changed the history and the
story of Happy
Flops.
This is the one day, this is the people that all our customers were pointing at
.
They were telling us that they saw some stories and a link of our product,
right?
And this is the start and the beginning of a fantastic journey of influencer
marketing
because this lady apparently here, I blur her face because we haven't got the
permission
to show this in this video and this is her husband, I will write husband here.
This lady had a story herself about our product because she never bought her
product, it was
actually her mother, her mother bought our Happy Flops and her mother went to
Spain
because she was living in Spain back then and her mother visited her daughter,
this woman
and she left our Happy Flops in her house.
So she was starting to use these slippers and Happy Flops on a daily basis and
when she
was recording her stories, people were seeing this.
So much up till it come to one point that people were asking, where did you get
these
slippers from?
They looked really comfortable and they looked really nice.
So she asked her mother, boom, mom, where did you get these slippers from?
Mother sent her a link, she sent her a link and then the plant lady, I call her
, posted
the link, one story and from that literally, I think in less than six hours,
six hours,
she sold for $10,000, it was incredible.
So this story changed completely the direction of our company because what did
I do?
I contacted this lady when I found out about these, the customers and I asked
her where
she was living, she told me the story about her mother and everything and then
I went,
I bought some tickets for Spain without asking her and when I arrived at the
city that she
was living in, I texted her, I said, hey, I'm here doing some family stuff,
could you
meet me?
We met for a coffee and a dinner and we had a blasting time and we really made
friends
and I asked her if we could do a paid collaboration because she already sold
for $10,000 basically
for free so I thought, all right, let's pay her and see what we can do for
collaboration.
So I paid her and we agreed on a price, actually the price I could tell you
guys, the price
was $1,500 USD and I could tell you directly that this was really cheap, this
was really
cheap.
So what happened next?
She agreed to do a collaboration, she did a video for me to approve and then
she posted
on her social media.
So what happened was that once she posted something really insanely happened,
she posted
the paid collaboration that we paid $1,500 USD for and then she sold for City,
USD in
the same amount of hours because in influencer marketing when you find a
performing influencer,
the amount of sales 80% usually comes the first six hours usually.
So she sold for this much and it completely changed the direction of my mindset
in ecommerce
of course and I think this would happen to anyone, anyone watching this video,
if a person
sells for 60,000 in revenue in her own channel by a story that will make you
think and reflect
and probably become obsessed about influencer marketing which was the thing
that happened.
This turned out for us to believe in this, right?
Of course anybody who would see these results will believe in this, so this
turned out into
invest in more.
We invested and then in the third, in the fourth, in the fifth influencer but
we did
everything I lost, lost all money because to be honest guys, this lady here, I
call her
the plant lady again, it was a grace, it was even I could say luck because as
you already
imagine and as you already know, not every influencer will do these crazy
results.
So we continue to invest in influencers, we try to find similar influencers, we
try to
find lookalikes and try to understand and we just kept investing, kept
investing in around
the 10th or 15th test like of influencer tests that we did, we found another
influencer that
sold for 50,000 as well.
And that's we continue it.
We made a lot of losses, right, after every investment that we did from every
influencer
until we found another one and then another one and then another one.
And that's basically the way we managed to find after four years from 20 to 30
influencers
that basically could sell these results.
So from all from 50 to 100k in six hours, right?
Because we never gave up, that's the thing and that's the key we continue.
And if you wonder how we were managed to afford this, it's because we used all
the profits
from our ads to keep looking for influencers.
All the profits from our ads were basically the fuel to keep investing in influ
encers
until we found them.
And we tried it all.
We tried it all.
We invested in young influencers, in old influencers and influencers that had
massive followers.
We did try it all and we still didn't understand.
However, once in a while we found this golden mine who could sell for 50 to 100
k in six
hours.
So once we found enough people that actually could sell this amount of money,
we started
to actually understand.
We found pattern because if you have 20 influencers that all of these 20 are
selling for millions
of dollars, millions of USD, you could just put them on the side of each other
on a map
and start to dig, to look what are these 20 doing the same that is a pattern?
What are they doing that all the 190 other influencers are not doing?
Because basically this is 10% of 200 influencers that we tested, 200 tests, 20
stands for 80%
of our entire revenue.
That's crazy numbers, right?
What do these 20 have in common?
That is what we found out.
That is what we try to understand.
And this leaves us to the real knowledge what you came for.
And I personally actually like to call this social selling because in the end
of the day,
what influencers are doing is living a social life, sharing this social life
online with
people and by doing this, they gain trust, they can gain trust because, yeah,
again,
in this case, only 20 of these influencers really gained a lot of trust.
Meanwhile, 180 people that we tested didn't have much trust at all.
So if we continue what we learned from this, when we became experts, it's first
that we
understood what influencer marketing is not.
This is very, very important for you guys to listen clearly.
Because a lot of you guys, and we get this every week, brands that reach out to
me, to
my partners, they invested in these influencers, they didn't work, why can you
explain why?
Like, we get these questions so many times, and that's also why we do in this
Zoom video.
And all the time, the basis of the decision of these people when they invest in
influencers
is basically this.
How many followers they have?
If there is anything relatable between the product that they sell and the influ
encer,
for example, if I'm a brand that I sell gym clothes, then it means that I only
looking
for gym influencers that are doing gymnastic or going to the gym.
This is what is called niche match, and this also has nothing to do with influ
encer marketing.
And then the most favorite world of them are engagement rate.
What is the engagement rate?
What is the impressions?
Or are they rich?
Look, engagement rate, impressions, reach, etc.
This is metrics that we actually never look at.
This is absolutely something that we never, ever look at.
Because when we did from the beginning, because this is what people teach you,
this is what
online teach you, this is what the platforms try to teach you to look at.
So that's also why we also looked at this in the beginning and yeah, it didn't
work.
Because a lot of people, when they think about influencers, you know what they
feel like?
See, no.
This is what a lot of brands are saying to us.
We feel like influencers is like a casino.
We invest, put some money into it, and we never know if we will get us any
return.
It feels like a casino.
And this is also something that we felt.
Look guys, we invest in 200 influencers.
Of course, we lost a lot of money like in a casino.
And we also didn't understand until we actually did, after doing so many
failures.
And then we found out what is the pattern.
Let's get to the nice and good things about this, all right?
What did we learn after so much failure?
Learn.
You have to learn guys.
This is the path to any success.
And if any of you guys are running any kind of business, e-commerce or whatever
, and you
are seeing some kind of results, it's because you learned.
You learn by a lot of mistakes and failures.
That's why failures and mistakes is the recipe to get real data, real lessons
that makes
you take better decisions, right?
This is what we are here for as a business owner.
What did we learn guys?
We found out three pillars.
Wow, this is the first lesson why other influencers sell and why some other
influencers doesn't
sell.
It's based on these three pillars, guys, authenticity, authority, and de-
connection.
Look guys, I will show you this, what it means in practicality, all right?
Don't need to worry.
But you have to listen first.
You have to listen because the theory of everything is really important to
listen to
and to understand.
So then when I show you this in practicality, when I will share my screen and
show you the
influencers and show you how we actually measure this and look at this, you
will understand.
But you have to understand the theory behind this, all right?
So what does it mean with authenticity?
Look, these three pillars generate something that we call trust, all right?
And this has all the logic and sense.
Authenticity, if you are a good marketer and you are listening to this right
now, you should
know authenticity always wins because authenticity is unique, it's real, right?
So behind authenticity, we do have this real, raw, unique, basically influ
encers that are
being just fucking real, sorry my language, but it's true.
It's so many influencers that are just copy-pasting.
It's a little bit like e-commerce brands.
What e-commerce brands becomes the biggest ones, right?
Which ones?
Do you think that it's the ones that are copying, pasting all the other brands,
what
they are doing?
No, it's the brands, yeah, that might be copying, pasting some things, but they
are also doing
something real, something unique, something own.
And this is really rare in the influencer industry.
The first thing you should learn.
Authority, what do I mean with this?
We go back to this.
To our beautiful lady, the plant lady, do you know what her channel was about?
Plants, that's why I call her the plant lady.
And this gave her authority.
She was and she is an expert on plants.
Which means that she already possessed a level of trust from her audience.
It doesn't really matter what authority she has, but she has it.
She has authority about plants and seeds and garden, stuff like this.
This is important because this means that she already created some kind of
authority
on her channel, which is really important.
And this is the pattern on all our 20 high performing influencers.
They have this.
They have some kind of authority in any field.
It doesn't matter if it's like journalists, if it's books, it's if plants, if
it's kitchen,
it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter if you sell kitchen things and you need to have authority to
figure
within kitchen.
It could help, potentially, but it really doesn't matter because in the end of
the day,
all of these people are just human beings.
If they have authority within kitchen, it's great.
But also these people wear clothing, right?
Also these people might do some sport, also these people might do some, for
example, camping,
whatever you sell, you could connect it to these people.
It doesn't really matter if it's connected to your own brand.
It could potentially help, but it doesn't really matter.
That's what I am trying to teach you.
But what matters is that they do have some kind of authority.
Our experts and they have a track record about something, which creates also
trust, right?
For example, this plant lady, she's amazing in recommending how to make the
best three
in lemons or apples or tomatoes, but she also wears clothes and slippers.
When she just recommends something by, not by accident, but from a place which
is very
genuine, people will believe her, because she already has authority within
something,
which means that people already trust her, which means she could recommend
anything.
Now deep connection, this is the most interesting part.
Deep connection means that these influencers, this 20 that has generated, by
the way, 70%
of 80 million by now, it's a lot.
It's a lot.
20 influencers stands for 70% of 80 million in revenue, right?
You should really assimilate that information.
It's a lot.
It's so powerful and you have to listen and you have to learn this, right?
Deep connection.
Deep connection means that these influencers have created some kind of
relationship with
the audience.
You have a connection and you know how you could tell this is because the
audience feels
like they know this person, this influencer.
What does it mean?
For example, let's say we speak about an influencer that a lot of people feel
like they know,
right?
Let's say King Kardashian, right?
The Kardashian team or the strongest man on the planet, strongest man planet,
all right?
I would teach you something extremely, extremely important here.
A lot of brands goes to this kind of figure, this man on the planet.
I sell supplements, so I shall go to the strongest man on the planet and
promote my
product, right?
Then what happens?
They sell zero.
Why?
I have so many people asking, why?
I invested in the biggest tennis player.
I invested in the best football player of my country, but it didn't sell
anything.
Why?
Because the audience doesn't feel like they know them.
They don't feel like they know them because they, how could they know them if
the only
thing they see on media is that they are the strongest man on the planet.
They are lifting heavy weights, they are doing all these contests,
championships, whatever,
but they don't know them.
At least they don't feel they know them because why they don't have any kind of
relationship
with this man or this figure.
However, Kim, by the way, expeditions, you could believe and think have
opinions that
she is bad, she is fake, she is whatever, but the recent audience, that really
feels
like they know Kim and why is that happening because Kim has exposed herself on
all kinds
of shape and forms on media, TV programs, radio, live shows, broadcast, all the
things
so people are watching her.
They are seeing how she talks, what she thinks about, what she talks about,
they understand
her personality, so the people who actually likes her buys from her.
Whatever she will sell, people will buy because they feel like they know her
and some people
really like her, they feel trust with her.
Not everyone, but the people who does.
The reason they buy is because they feel like they know Kim.
This is the difference.
So now, whatever you are going to invest in an influencer, the ask should be,
do people
think they know this person?
Pretty easy to get the right answer.
The audience doesn't feel they know you only because you are famous, because
you are the
best athlete in this field, for example.
But you might be so exposed to media as an influencer, so people really believe
they
know you, they know who you are, how you think, what you eat, what you don't
eat, then it
might get interesting because then you have found an influencer that has
influenced people
and made them believe that they have a relationship.
So this is the first chapter, all right, and I will obviously show you how this
actually
manifests in reality on social media and on media itself.
How does this 20 people actually do, and what do they do to create this deep
connection?
And to create the relationship and how they make people believe and feel that
they know
them, perfect.
I hope this first chapter makes sense, and let's go to the next one, once you
feel that
to follow this information that you have assimilated.